{
  "title": "California DMV Regular Driver (Class C) Written Test",
  "ref": "https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/driver-education-and-safety/educational-materials/sample-driver-license-dl-knowledge-tests/",
  "test": [
    {
      "id": "T1Q1",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You may drive off of the paved roadway to pass another vehicle:",
      "A": "A. If the shoulder is wide enough to accommodate your vehicle.",
      "B": "B. If the vehicle ahead of you is turning left.",
      "C": "C. Under no circumstances."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q2",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "You are approaching a railroad crossing with no warning devices and are unable to see 400 feet down the tracks in one direction. The speed limit is:",
      "A": "A. 15 mph.",
      "B": "B. 20 mph.",
      "C": "C. 25 mph."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q3",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "When parking your vehicle parallel to the curb on a level street:",
      "A": "A. Your front wheels must be turned toward the street.",
      "B": "B. Your wheels must be within 18 inches of the curb.",
      "C": "C. One of your rear wheels must touch the curb."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q4",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "When you are merging onto the freeway, you should be driving:",
      "A": "A. At or near the same speed as the traffic on the freeway.",
      "B": "B. 5 to 10 MPH slower than the traffic on the freeway.",
      "C": "C. The posted speed limit for traffic on the freeway."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q5",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "When driving in fog, you should use your:",
      "A": "A. Fog lights only.",
      "B": "B. High beams.",
      "C": "C. Low beams."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q6",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "A white painted curb means:",
      "A": "A. Loading zone for freight or passengers.",
      "B": "B. Loading zone for passengers or mail only.",
      "C": "C. Loading zone for freight only."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q7",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "A school bus ahead of you in your lane is stopped with red lights flashing. You should:",
      "A": "A. Stop, then proceed when you think all of the children have exited the bus.",
      "B": "B. Slow to 25 MPH and pass cautiously.",
      "C": "C. Stop as long as the red lights are flashing."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q8",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "California's \"Basic Speed Law\" says:",
      "A": "A. You should never drive faster than posted speed limits.",
      "B": "B. You should never drive faster than is safe for current conditions.",
      "C": "C. The maximum speed limit in California is 70 mph on certain freeways."
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q9",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "You just sold your vehicle. You must notify the DMV within ___ days.",
      "A": "A. 5",
      "B": "B. 10",
      "C": "C. 15"
    },
    {
      "id": "T1Q10",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "To avoid last minute moves, you should be looking down the road to where your vehicle will be in about ______________.",
      "A": "A. 5 to 10 seconds",
      "B": "B. 10 to 15 seconds",
      "C": "C. 15 to 20 seconds"
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q1",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You are about to make a left turn. You must signal continuously during the last ____ feet before the turn.",
      "A": "A. 50",
      "B": "B. 75",
      "C": "C. 100"
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q2",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "Which of the following statements about blind spots is true?",
      "A": "A. They are eliminated if you have one outside mirror on each side of the vehicle.",
      "B": "B. Large trucks have bigger blind spots than most passenger vehicles.",
      "C": "C. Blind spots can be checked by looking in your rear view mirrors."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q3",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You have been involved in a minor traffic collision with a parked vehicle and you can't find the owner. You must:",
      "A": "A. Leave a note on the vehicle.",
      "B": "B. Report the accident without delay to the city police or, in unincorporated areas, to the CHP.",
      "C": "C. Both of the above."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q4",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "Unless otherwise posted the speed limit in a residential area is ____.",
      "A": "A. 20 mph",
      "B": "B. 25 mph",
      "C": "C. 30 mph"
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q5",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You may legally block an intersection:",
      "A": "A. When you entered the intersection on the green light.",
      "B": "B. During rush hour traffic.",
      "C": "C. Under no circumstances."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q6",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "When parking uphill on a two-way street with no curb, your front wheels should be:",
      "A": "A. Turned to the left (toward the street).",
      "B": "B. Turned to the right (away from the street).",
      "C": "C. Parallel with the pavement."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q7",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "With a Class C drivers license a person may drive:",
      "A": "A. A 3-axle vehicle if the Gross Vehicle Weight is less than 6,000 pounds.",
      "B": "B. Any 3-axle vehicle regardless of the weight.",
      "C": "C. A vehicle pulling two trailers."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q8",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "To turn left from a multilane one-way street onto a one-way street, you should start your turn from:",
      "A": "A. Any lane (as long as it is safe).",
      "B": "B. The lane closest to the left curb.",
      "C": "C. The lane in the center of the road."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q9",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "If you are involved in a traffic collision, you are required to complete and submit a written report (SR1) to the DMV:",
      "A": "A. Only if you or the other driver is injured.",
      "B": "B. If there is property damage in excess of $1,000 or if there are any injuries.",
      "C": "C. Only if you are at fault."
    },
    {
      "id": "T2Q10",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "Roadways are the most slippery:",
      "A": "A. During a heavy downpour.",
      "B": "B. After it has been raining for awhile.",
      "C": "C. The first rain after a dry spell."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q1",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "You may not park your vehicle:",
      "A": "A. On the side of the freeway in an emergency.",
      "B": "B. Next to a red painted curb.",
      "C": "C. Within 100 feet of an elementary school."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q2",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "You must notify the DMV within 5 days if you:",
      "A": "A. Sell or transfer your vehicle.",
      "B": "B. Fail a smog test for your vehicle.",
      "C": "C. Get a new prescription for lenses or contacts."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q3",
      "answer": "B",
      "question": "Two sets of solid, double, yellow lines that are two or more feet apart:",
      "A": "A. May be crossed to enter or exit a private driveway.",
      "B": "B. May not be crossed for any reason.",
      "C": "C. Should be treated as a separate traffic lane."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q4",
      "answer": "D",
      "question": "You want to make a right turn at an upcoming intersection. You should slow down and:",
      "A": "A. Move toward the left side of your lane.",
      "B": "B. Avoid driving in the bicycle lane.",
      "C": "C. Signal for 100 feet before turning."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q5",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You are driving on a freeway posted for 65 MPH. The traffic is traveling at 70 MPH. You may legally drive:",
      "A": "A. 70 mph or faster to keep up with the speed of traffic.",
      "B": "B. Between 65 mph and 70 mph.",
      "C": "C. No faster than 65 mph."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q6",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "It is illegal to park your vehicle:",
      "A": "A. In an unmarked crosswalk.",
      "B": "B. Within three feet of a private driveway.",
      "C": "C. In a bicycle lane."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q7",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "The safest precaution that you can take regarding the use of cellular phones and driving is:",
      "A": "A. Use hands-free devices so you can keep both hands on the steering wheel.",
      "B": "B. Keep your phone within easy reach so you won't need to take your eyes off the road.",
      "C": "C. Review the number before answering a call."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q8",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "If you have a green light, but traffic is blocking the intersection, you should:",
      "A": "A. Stay out of the intersection until traffic clears.",
      "B": "B. Enter the intersection and wait until traffic clears.",
      "C": "C. Merge into another lane and try to go around the traffic."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q9",
      "answer": "C",
      "question": "You are getting ready to make a right turn. You should:",
      "A": "A. Signal and turn immediately.",
      "B": "B. Stop before entering the right lane and let all other traffic go first.",
      "C": "C. Slow down or stop, if necessary, and then make the turn."
    },
    {
      "id": "T3Q10",
      "answer": "A",
      "question": "You must obey instructions from school crossing guards:",
      "A": "A. At all times.",
      "B": "B. Only during school hours.",
      "C": "C. Unless you do not see any children present."
    }
  ]
}